<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archer Benthic Ecology Lab</title>
    <link>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Archer Benthic Ecology Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Archer Benthic Ecology Lab</title>
      <link>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/main/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Archer Benthic Ecology Lab at Louisiana Universities Marine Consortium LUMCON . We are a group of ecologists who spend our time exploring the fundamental principles that underpin the structure and function of biogenic habitats, or habitats formed by plants or animals. We use a combination of observational and experimental approaches to elucidate the role that habitat forming species play in maintaining biodiversity and ecosystem function in the Anthropocene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Ethics</title>
      <link>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/labethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/labethics/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to Sammy Katta for creating the original design for this poster. By using this poster we, as a lab, commit to continuous allyship for marginalized and underrepresented communities. The full pledge can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Members</title>
      <link>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/people/</guid>
      <description>Stephanie K. Archer, PI Dr. Archer completed her PhD at North Carolina State University where she worked in the Layman Lab studying how sponges alter community composition and ecosystem function in tropical and subtropical nearshore marine ecosystems. She then moved on to work for Fisheries and Oceans Canada in multiple capacities. There she studied species interactions and ecosystem function of Glass Sponge Reefs and worked to develop efficient monitoring methods grounded in a strong understanding of the behavior and ecology of keystone species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Research</title>
      <link>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Study systems Biogenic habitats, or habitats formed by living organisms, such as coral reefs, sponge grounds, and seagrass beds are among the most biodiverse ecosystems in the oceans. They provide us with many ecosystem services from food production and natural products chemistry to shoreline protection and storm buffering. They are also among the most impacted systems, suffering from a wide range of anthropogenic and natural stressors that combine to threaten their continued existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospective Students</title>
      <link>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/prospectivestudents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/prospectivestudents/</guid>
      <description>Come work with us! Funded opportunities Watch this space for an announcement coming soon.
Interested students I am always excited to speak with students interested in working with me. If this is you, please email me at sarcher at lumcon.edu with:
 A cover letter explaining what type of research you&amp;rsquo;re interested in and why you want to work with me. Your CV  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archerbenthicecologylab.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Links to publications are provided. If you cannot freely access a publication DO NOT PAY. Instead, please email Stephanie at sarcher at lumcon.edu and she will send you a copy.
Archer, SK, AS Kahn, M Thiess, L Law, SP Leys, SC Johannessen, CA Layman, L Burke, and A Dunham.	2020. Foundation Species Abundance Influences Food Web Topology on Glass Sponge Reefs. Frontiers in	Marine Science 7:549478. DOI: 10.3389/fmars.2020.549478
Archer, SK, G Dennison, L Tryon, S Byers, and A Dunham.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
